{"test_questions": [[{"question": "How many molecules of ATPs are synthesized per NADH oxidation?", "opta": "2", "optb": "1", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is the TCA cycle the central pathway of metabolism of the cell?", "opta": "It occurs in the center of the cell", "optb": "Its intermediates are commonly used by other metabolic reactions", "optc": "All other metabolic pathways depend upon it", "optd": "None of  the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In what form does the product of glycolysis enter the TCA cycle?", "opta": "AcetylCoA", "optb": "Pyruvate", "optc": "NADH", "optd": "Glucose", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Malate-asparatate shuttle operates in", "opta": "lungs and liver", "optb": "heart and liver", "optc": "pancreas and liver", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Oxidation of a molecule involves", "opta": "gain of electron", "optb": "loss of electron", "optc": "gain of proton", "optd": "loss of proton", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During cellular respiration, most of the ATP made, is generated by", "opta": "oxidative phosphorylation", "optb": "photophosphorylation", "optc": "glycolysis", "optd": "substrate-level phosphorylation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Important function of cholesterol is to", "opta": "modulate fluidity", "optb": "enhance blood circulation", "optc": "prevent bile salts formation", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To stop ATP synthesis which chemical is generally used?", "opta": "DNSA", "optb": "2,4 dinitrophenol", "optc": "DDT", "optd": "None of the chemical can stop ATP synthesis", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The enzymes of the TCA cycle in a eukaryotic cell are located in the", "opta": "nucleus", "optb": "mitochondria", "optc": "plasma membrane", "optd": "lysosomal bodies", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Citric acid cycle occurs in", "opta": "cytoplasm", "optb": "mitochondria", "optc": "endoplasmic reticulum", "optd": "golgi bodies", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most multi-cellular organisms obtain energy for the synthesis of ATP during oxidative phosphorylation from", "opta": "high energy phosphate compounds", "optb": "a proton gradient across the inner mitochondrial membrane", "optc": "a proton gradient across the cell membrane", "optd": "a proton gradient across the outer mitochondrial membrane", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Standard redox potential for a substance is measured under standard condition and is expressed as", "opta": "mili-Ampere", "optb": "Volt", "optc": "without unit", "optd": "Ohm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most of the enzymes of the citric acid cycle in a eukaryotic cell are located in the", "opta": "inner mitochondrial membrane", "optb": "cytosol", "optc": "mitochondrial matrix", "optd": "intermembrane space", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A positive redox potential means substance has", "opta": "lower affinity for electron", "optb": "higher affinity for electron", "optc": "lower affinity for proton", "optd": "higher affinity for proton", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The end product of glycolysis is pyruvate, which enters the citric acid cycle after being converted to", "opta": "acetic acid", "optb": "acetyl-CoA", "optc": "acetaldehyde", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Energy that is released from glucose during respiration but not transferred to ATP bonds can be detected as", "opta": "CO2", "optb": "AMP", "optc": "ADP", "optd": "heat", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is involved in energy production?", "opta": "Generation of proton gradients across membranes", "optb": "Transport of electrons on organic molecules", "optc": "Conversion of compounds with high energy to those of low energy", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following enzyme does not take part in the TCA cycle?", "opta": "Citrate synthase", "optb": "Iso-citrate dehydrogenase", "optc": "Pyruvate dehydrogenase", "optd": "Malate dehydrogenase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first intermediate in TCA cycle is", "opta": "succinate", "optb": "fumerate", "optc": "citrate", "optd": "malate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cholesterol can be synthesized de novo in", "opta": "pancreas", "optb": "intestine", "optc": "liver", "optd": "cell membrane", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is not the intermediate of Kreb's cycle?", "opta": "Isocitrate", "optb": "Succinate", "optc": "Fumarate", "optd": "Stearate", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which one is not the main protein in electron transport chain?", "opta": "NADH dehydrogenase", "optb": "Cytochrome bc1 complex", "optc": "Cytochrome oxidase", "optd": "Citrate synthease", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many ATPs are produced during citric acid cycle?", "opta": "10", "optb": "13", "optc": "12", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The FADH2 and NADH produced by the oxidation of one acetyl-CoA results in the synthesis of about-", "opta": "3 ATPs", "optb": "6 ATPs", "optc": "11 ATPs", "optd": "15 ATPs", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In eukaryotes, electron transport occurs in", "opta": "membranes and mitochondria", "optb": "endoplasmic reticulum", "optc": "cytoplasm", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The catabolism of sugars and fatty acids is similar because", "opta": "both of these compounds are funnelled through the TC A/citric acid cycle", "optb": "both of these compounds generate redox energy during catabolism", "optc": "both of these compounds generate chemical energy during catabolism", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}